<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The Account of the proceedings at Guild-Hall on the 19th instant, 1682, for the election of a sheriff to stand with Mr. North for the insuing year by the livery of the several companies of the city of London, giving an account of the most remarkable transactions and speeches that were in the Common-Hall during their being assembled on that occasion.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1682</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 5 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2013-12">2013-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A25706</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing A356</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R7221</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">11897770</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 11897770</idno>
            <idno type="VID">50563</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A25706)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 50563)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 3:9)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The Account of the proceedings at Guild-Hall on the 19th instant, 1682, for the election of a sheriff to stand with Mr. North for the insuing year by the livery of the several companies of the city of London, giving an account of the most remarkable transactions and speeches that were in the Common-Hall during their being assembled on that occasion.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for J. Heathcoate,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1682.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from colophon.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>North, Dudley, --  Sir, 1641-1691.</term>
               <term>City of London (England). --  Court of Common Council.</term>
               <term>London (England) --  Politics and government.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-06</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:50563:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>THE ACCOUNT OF THE PROCEEDINGS AT Guild-Hall On the <hi>19th</hi> Inſtant, 1682. For the Election of a SHERIFF To Stand with Mr. NORTH For the Inſuing Year; by the Livery of the ſeveral Companies of the CITY of LONDON: Giving an account of the moſt remarkable Tranſacti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons and Speeches that were in the Common-Hall, during their being Aſſembled on that occaſion.</head>
            <opener>
               <dateline>Guild-Hall, <date>Sept. <hi>19.</hi>
                  </date>
               </dateline>
            </opener>
            <p>THIS being the day of Election appointed by the Right Honourable the Lord Mayor and Court of Aldermen, upon their Siting on <hi>Thurſday</hi> laſt; in order thereunto Precepts being Iſſued out, the Livery of the ſeveral Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>panies Aſſembled in Common-Hall, where (after ſome Tarrience) the Right Honourable the Lord Mayor, with the Alder<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men, attended by Mr. Common-Serjeant, Town-Clerk, and Mr. Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon
<pb facs="tcp:50563:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>Cryer, came upon the <hi>Huſtings</hi> according to the cuſtom of this City, and the late Order, for Electing a perſon to ſtand with Mr. <hi>North</hi> for Sheriff for the enſuing year; when after ſome had cryed Election, Election, and others on the contrary, Choſen, Choſen, <hi>Papillion, Du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>boice,</hi> no Confirmation, no new Election, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> then Silence being pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>claimed, the Common-Cryer came forward, and made Proclama<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, <hi>viz.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>All Gentlemen, Citizens of <hi>London,</hi> who upon Precept have been ſummoned this day to Aſſemble in Common-Hall, for the Electing a perſon to ſtand Sheriff with <hi>Dudley North</hi> Eſq; for the inſuing year.—He would have proceeded, but was interrupted by loud Shouts, and crying No, no, no, no new Election, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Then Mr. Common-Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeant came forward with a Paper in his hand, in which were the names of ſuch as was intended to be put up, but ſuch was the clamour of no <hi>North,</hi> no new Election, that although he read them, yet few could hear him; ſo that he was forced to retire: and then the preſent Sheriffs came forward, and put the Queſtion to the Common Hall, whether they would ſtand by the choice of <hi>Tho Papillion</hi> and <hi>John Duboice,</hi> or proceed to a new Election? Whereupon there was a cry of <hi>Papillion, Duboice,</hi> no new Election, for near a quarter of an Hour, mixed with Hiſſes on the other part, many Voating for a new Election; the which Mr. Common-Serjeant perceiving, nominated Mr. <hi>Rich,</hi> where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon the Hall was divided, but the noiſe ſuch that nothing could be heard: So that after many Proclamations for ſilence, and none could be procured, though the Sheriffs were not wanting to uſe their utmoſt endeavours to procure it, the Right Honourable the Lord Mayor gave order for diſſolving the Court, which was accordingly done by Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clamation: Whereupon the Lord Mayor cauſed the Sword to be taken up, and departed the Court, together with the Aldermen, moſt of them retiring into the Council-Chamber, when as Mr. Sheriff <hi>Shute</hi> gone out of the Court, was called back, and according to the Sheriffs direction, the Pole adjourned for an Hour, to conſider whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther the Common-Hall would Pole for a Confirmation of <hi>Thomas Pap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pillion</hi> and <hi>John Duboice,</hi> according to the former Election, againſt ſuch as were nominated in oppoſition: After which the Sheriffs left the Court, no perſon being by them nominated to Pole in competition with Mr. <hi>Pappillion</hi> and Mr. <hi>Duboice,</hi> the perſons formerly ſtanding in com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>petition with Mr. <hi>North</hi> and Mr. <hi>Box.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>When about an Hour after, the Common-Hall again Aſſembling, Clerks were ordered by the Sheriffs to take the Pole for <hi>John Duboice, Themqs Pappillion, Dudley North</hi> Eſq; and Mr. <hi>Peter Rich;</hi> ſo that the Books being prepared, they Sealed them themſelves at either end of the Common-Hall, being about Twelve in number: but it was ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerved, though many Poled for Mr. <hi>Papillion</hi> and Mr. <hi>Duboice;</hi> yet but very few, and thoſe moſt of them not preſent at the diſſolving of the Court, Poling for Mr. <hi>North</hi> and Mr. <hi>Rich,</hi> the reſt aledging, that the Right Honourable the Lord Mayor had diſſolved the Court, and therefore they looked upon their Poling as ineffectual; yet the Pole continued till the Evening, and great was the diſproportion of Hands, Mr. <hi>Papillion</hi> and Mr. <hi>Duboice</hi> having the majority, by reaſon of ſmall oppoſition.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON:</hi> Printed for <hi>J. Heathcoate,</hi> 1682.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
